Guide to the Diana Trilling Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: Writings, 1929-1996
  - Subseries III.2: Articles and Essays, 1929-1996
    Subseries 2 is comprised of Diana Trilling's shorter writings in the form of articles and essays. The majority of the pieces were published, although there are some early works that were rejected. Many of the texts have accompanying documentation in the form of correspondence concerning the publication and editing of the text, research notes, and reviews after publication. In addition to the traditional articles and essays, lectures, speeches, book reviews and drafts are found in this subseries. Of particular interest are the columns Diana Trilling wrote for The Nation called "Fiction in Review" and her essays on Marilyn Monroe and the cultural impact of the film, Easy Rider. Also included in this subseries are two plays, Snitken written with Bettina Sinclair and The Young Wives' Tale both of which are from the 1930s.
    - Address to the Annual Conference of the Child Study Association, 1958 March 24 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - "Aldous Huxley," 1974 (review) (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - "America and The Quiet American 1956 May 15 (review) (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - "America through Dark Spectacles," 1953 July (review) (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - "The American Female," undated (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - "And Life Comes Knocking at the Window," undated (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Award Presentation in Honor of Lionel Trilling, 1976 December 6 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - "The Baby-Nurses," 1952 April (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - "A Bang and a Whimper," undated (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - "Beppo," 1939 January-February (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - "The Bird with the Broken Wing," undated (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - "The Birthday Party," undated (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - Carnegie Corporation "American Shelf List," 1956 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - "Celebrating with Dr. Leary," 1967 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - "The Challenger," undated (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Columbia Uprising of 1968, 1968 (notes) (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Commentary Symposium, undated, 1967-1975 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - "The Concerto," 1968 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - "The Conscience of the Intellectual," 1960 May-June (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - "Couples," 1968 April (review) (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - "Cultural Exchange," 1958 June (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - "The Cultural Mode in Political Criticism," 1968 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - "Culture and Anarchy," undated (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - "Culture, Biology and Our Sexual Roles," 1970 June (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - "The Culture of the Colleges: Oxford and Columbia," 1965 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Diana Trilling: Biographical Sketch, 1976 (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - "Dorothy Thompson," 1973 March (review) (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - "Easy Rider and Its Critics," 1970 April (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - "The Education of a Woman," 1950 (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - "Eight to Nine," 1936 May-June (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - "Etching," undated (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - "Feminism and Women's Liberation," 1974 May (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - "Footnote to My Life as a Critic"--Correspondence, 1991-1996 (Box 31, Folder 21)
    - "Footnote to My Life as a Critic"--Drafts, 1995-1996 (Box 31, Folder 22)
    - "Frieda Lawrence," 1973 May (review) (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - "The Girls of Camp Lenore"--Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - "The Girls of Camp Lenore"--Draft, [1995] (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - "Goronwy-and Others"
      - Correspondence, 1994-1996 (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - Drafts, 1995 (Box 32, Folder 5)
      - Notes, undated, 1976, 1994 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Germany, 1967 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - "H.G. Wells and Rebecca West," 1974 (review) (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - "History of Five Decades," [1976] (notes) (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - "The Image of Women in Contemporary Literature," 1964 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - "The Incas and Their Civilization," undated (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - "The Influence of Contemporary Literary Culture on the Gifted College Woman," 1964 May (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Jimmy Carter, 1976 (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Junior Bazaar--"About Books," 1946-1947 (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - "A Journal of the Plague Years," 1973 June (review) (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - "Lawrence and the Movements of Modern Culture," 1973 (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - "Leaving England," 1960s (notes) (Box 32, Folder 17)
    - "Letter from Abroad," 1966-1967 (Box 32, Folder 18)
    - Letters to the Editor
      - General, 1986-1990 (Box 32, Folder 19)
      - Commentary, 1968 June (Box 32, Folder 20)
      - New York Review of Books, 1967, 1988 (Box 32, Folder 21)
      - The New York Times, 1977, 1984-1986 (Box 32, Folder 22)
      - The New York Times Book Review, 1974-1986 (Box 32, Folder 23)
      - Partisan Review, 1955, 1965-1967 (Box 32, Folder 24)
      - The Twentieth Century, 1953 August 12 (Box 32, Folder 25)
    - "The Liberal as Intellectual," undated (notes) (Box 32, Folder 26)
    - "Life in the 1930s," 1960 (Box 32, Folder 27)
    - "The Life of the Amazon," 1942 (Box 32, Folder 28)
    - "Lost and Found," undated (Box 32, Folder 29)
    - "The Man with a Drum," undated (Box 32, Folder 30)
    - "Marilyn Monroe: The Meaning of Her Life and Death"
      - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 32, Folder 31)
      - Review, 1986 (Box 33, Folder 1)
      - Translation, 1991 July (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - "The Marriage of Elsie and John," undated (written under pseudonym of Margaret Sayles) (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - "Meeting with Mailer," undated (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - "Memo of a Visit," undated (notes) (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - "Miss Villette's in the Springtime," 1963 June (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - "The Namesake," 1930s (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - NMC Theatre Commentary, 1949 November 20 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - The Nation--"Fiction in Review"
      - 1942 June 27-1944 January 22 (Box 33, Folder 9)
      - 1944 January 29-1946 January 5 (Box 33, Folder 10)
      - 1946 January 26-1947 September 20 (Box 33, Folder 11)
      - 1947 October 11-1949 June 25 (Box 34, Folder 1)
      - Notebooks, 1943-1949 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Notes, undated, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - "Notes on the Trial of the Century," 1995 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - "The Nurse," undated (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - "Of Husbands and Wives," 1945 October 13 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - "On the First Anniversary of President Kennedy's Death," 1964 Summer (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - "On the Steps of Low Library," 1968-1969 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - O'Neill, Son and Artist, 1973 November (review) (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - "Onty Emma," 1936 May (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - "The Other Night at Columbia," 1958 (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - "Out of Phase in Palermo," undated (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Poems--General, undated (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - Poems--Children, 1939 (Box 34, Folder 14)
    - The Portable D.H. Lawrence, 1946 (notes) (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - "Portrait of a Marriage," 1974 (review) (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - "The Prodigious Trio," undated (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - "The Psychology of Plenty," 1945 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Puccini, 1970 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Reader's Reports, 1943 August 25 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - "Reading by Ear"--Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Remarks at Aspen Institute Conference, 1975 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Reminiscence of Raymond Weaver, undated (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Response to Soviet Policies, 1959 January-February (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Reviews--General, 1942-1974 (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Reviews--New York Times, undated, 1948-1983 (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Reviewing the Forties, 1978 Fall (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - "The Riddle of Who's Afraid of Virginia Woolf?" 1963 Sping (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - "The River Bank," undated (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - "The Rope Dancers" and "Time Remembered," undated (Box 35, Folder 16)
    - "The Sale of a Work of Art," 1942 May (Box 35, Folder 17)
    - Selected Letters of D.H. Lawrence, 1957-1960 (Box 35, Folder 18)
    - "The Self as Subject," 1983 February 23 (lecture) (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - "Self-Mythologizing and Lillian Hellman," 1962 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Snitken 1930 (play co-written with Bettina Sinclair) (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Speaking of Literature and Society, 1980 February (editor's foreword) (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Speeches
      - Overseas Press Club, 1956 (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - Pasternak, 1958 (Box 36, Folder 6)
      - School for Ethical Culture, 1958 September (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - Women's Faculty Club, 1969 May 7 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Statement Read to Board of Directors, American Committee for Cultural Freedom, 1961 January 10 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Toodles Stories, 1939 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - "Thursday the Beats, Tuesday the Analysts," 1975 April (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - "A Train of Powder," undated (review) (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - "The Uncomplaining Ackerley," 1969 August (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - Untitled Short Story, 1929 Summer (set in Florence) (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - "Virginia Woolf's Special Realm," undated (review) (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - Visit to Camelot, undated (Box 36, Folder 16)
    - "What Is Happening to Love?, 1959 Summer (Box 36, Folder 17)
    - The Widowed," undated (Box 36, Folder 18)
    - "The Wisdom of Dr. Benjamin Spock," 1970 (Box 36, Folder 19)
    - "Women and Their Minds," 1959 July (Box 36, Folder 20)
    - "Women's Lib," 1971 April (Box 36, Folder 21)
    - The Young Wives' Tale, 1930s (play) (Box 36, Folder 22)
- Series IV: Subject Files, 1924-1996
  Within Series IV are topical records used by Diana Trilling. Some of the files are research background for articles, legal and financial information concerning the Lionel Trilling Estate, Correspondence and accompanying documentation for the various publishing houses that Diana and Lionel Trilling worked with over the course of their careers, articles and clippings. The series is arranged into two subseries: Diana Trilling and Lionel Trilling.
  - Subseries IV.1: Diana Trilling, 1924-1996
    The first subseries contains records documenting Diana Trilling's professional career as a critic and writer as well as her role as caretaker of her husbands literary estate. Records address Trilling's political activities, such as the American Committee for Cultural Freedom files and other professional and intellectual organizations which sought her support, public responses to her essays and lectures, and documents related to the creation and management of the Lionel Trilling Seminars. Clippings of articles about the Trillings and of potential essay topics and writings dedicated to Diana Trilling by other authors, notably Quentin Anderson and Lionel Trilling, are also held in this subseries. There is a substantial amount of material stemming from a series of oral histories conducted by Trilling on behalf of the Columbia University Oral History Department. Individuals interviewed consist primarily of Lionel Trilling's friends and intellectual colleagues from the 1930s through the 1950s. In addition to being the interviewer, Diana Trilling herself is the interviewee in several oral histories in this subseries, the most substantial being one conducted by Christopher Zinn. Please note that the dates of the Zinn interviews are not in chronological order. Trilling re-recorded many of the tapes due to poor transmission or personal reasons.
    - American Committee for Cultural Freedom (ACCF)--General, 1954-1969, 1983-1985 (Box 36, Folder 23)
    - American Committee for Cultural Freedom (ACCF)--Address, 1961 April 6 (Box 36, Folder 24)
    - The American Intellectual Elite, 1970, 1995 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - American Professors for Peace in the Middle East, 1980-1981 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - The American Scholar, 1974-1979 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Archive, 1983-1987 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Articles
      - "Clarence O. Baring and the Attempted Murder of Mrs. Baring," 1924 (Box 37, Folder 5)
      - "Diana Trilling Readies for the Next Political Battle," 1995 September (Box 37, Folder 6)
      - Trilling, Diana, 1979-1986 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Baruch, Elaine, 1978-1979 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Bibliography of Lionel Trilling's Text, 1986 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Brandeis Arts Commission, 1981-1983 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - "The Changing Myth of the Jew," 1978 (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Civilization--Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - Civilization--"Fame and Celebrity," 1996 (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - Clippings of Politics and Culture, 1925-1986 (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - Columbia College Today--Letters to the Editor, 1993-1994 (Box 37, Folder 15)
    - Columbia University Uprising, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Conant, Oliver, 1984 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Contracts and Copyright, 1962-1989 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Crank Letters, 1980-1995 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - "Daughters of the Middle Class," 1977 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - D.H. Lawrence--Criticism, 1970-1983 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - D.H. Lawrence--Reviews, 1947, 1958 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Diana Trilling Interviews
      - General, 1964-1967 (Box 38, Folder 8)
      - Alpern, Sarah, 1983 June 21 (Box 38, Folder 9)
      - Baruch, Elaine, 1979 August (Box 38, Folder 10)
      - Kaufman, Alan, undated (Box 38, Folder 11)
      - Radcliffe Tapes, undated (Box 38, Folder 12)
      - Zinn, Christopher
        - Tape I, 1982 September (Box 38, Folder 13)
        - Tape II, 1982 September (Box 38, Folder 14)
        - Tape III, 1982 September (Box 38, Folder 15)
        - Tape IV, 1982 October (Box 39, Folder 1)
        - Tape V, 1982 October (Box 39, Folder 2)
        - Tape VI, 1982 October (Box 39, Folder 3)
        - Tape VII, 1982 October (Box 39, Folder 4)
        - Tape VIII, 1982 November (Box 39, Folder 5)
        - Tape IX, 1982 November (Box 39, Folder 6)
        - Tape X, 1982 November (Box 39, Folder 7)
        - Tape XI, 1983 August (Box 39, Folder 8)
        - Tape XII, 1983 January (Box 39, Folder 9)
        - Tape XIII, 1983 January (Box 39, Folder 10)
        - Tape XIV, 1983 February (Box 40, Folder 1)
        - Tape XV, 1983 February (Box 40, Folder 2)
        - Tape XVI, 1983 February (Box 40, Folder 3)
        - Tape XVII, 1983 September (Box 40, Folder 4)
        - Tape XVIII, 1983 March (Box 40, Folder 5)
        - Tape XIX, 1983 March (Box 40, Folder 6)
        - Tape XX, 1983 March (Box 40, Folder 7)
        - Tape XXI, 1983 April (Box 40, Folder 8)
        - Tape XXII, 1983 April (Box 40, Folder 9)
        - Tape XXIII, 1983 April (Box 40, Folder 10)
        - Tape XXV, 1983 May (Box 40, Folder 11)
        - Tape XXVI, 1983 May (Box 41, Folder 1)
        - Tape XVII, 1983 May (Box 41, Folder 2)
        - Tape XVIII, 1983 June (Box 41, Folder 3)
        - Tape XXIX, 1983 June (Box 41, Folder 4)
        - Tape XXX, 1983 June (Box 41, Folder 5)
        - Tape XXXI, 1983 June (Box 41, Folder 6)
        - Tape XXXII, 1983 July (Box 41, Folder 7)
        - Tape XXXIII, 1983 July (Box 41, Folder 8)
        - Tape XXXIV, 1983 July (Box 41, Folder 9)
        - Tape XXXV, 1983 August (Box 41, Folder 10)
        - Tape XXXVI, 1984 January (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - Dwight Macdonald Interview, 1983 (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - Easy Rider and Its Critics, 1969-1970 (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - Ethergain, Edward, 1982-1992 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Eleanor and Hillary, 1996 January (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Genealogy, 1996 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Ginsberg, Allen--"Smoking Typewriters," 1975-1978 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Graham, Philip L., 1953-1956, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Guggenheim Application, 1990-1993 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Harcourt Brace Jovanovich
      - Contracts, 1982-1995 (Box 42, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence
        - 1968-1977 September (Box 42, Folder 8)
        - 1977 October-1980 (Box 42, Folder 9)
        - 1981-1992 (Box 42, Folder 10)
        - 1993-1996 (Box 43, Folder 1)
        - General, 1968-1993, (2 Folders) (Box 60, Folder 4 to 6)
        - Harris Case, 1980-1982 (Box 60, Folder 7)
        - Lionel Trilling Editions, 1976-1981 (Box 60, Folder 8)
      - Jovanovich, Peter, 1989-1991 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Legal Issues, 1965-1985 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Hellman, Lillian
      - Controversy, 1976-1977 (Box 43, Folder 4)
      - Death, 1984 (Box 43, Folder 5)
      - McCarthy Suit, 1980 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - History of Five Decades, 1968-1976 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Honorary Party for The Nation, 1944 June (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Hyde, Jim, 1995-1996 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - "Imagining Our Time: The Vocation of Diana Trilling," 1993 (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Irving Howe Interview Correspondence, 1994 (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Israel Visit, 1974-1977 (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - The Jewish Braille Institute of America, 1981-1983 (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - Kazin, Alfred--Lionel Trilling's Death, 1978, 1990 (Box 43, Folder 14)
    - Klingenstein, Susanne, 1992 March-April (Box 43, Folder 15)
    - Legal Issues, 1993-1995 (Box 43, Folder 16)
    - "The Liberated Heroine," 1977-1978 (lecture) (Box 43, Folder 17)
    - "Lionel Trilling, A Jew at Columbia," 1979 March-April (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Lionel Trilling--As Subject, 1978-1985 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - "Lionel Trilling and Allen Ginsberg," 1986 July 4 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Lionel Trilling Award, 1994 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Lionel Trilling Bibliography, 1991-1992 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Lionel Trilling Estate
      - Boyers, Robert, 1977-1978 (Box 44, Folder 6)
      - Chace, William, 1976-1979 (Box 44, Folder 7)
      - Christiansen Controversy, 1977-1979 (Box 44, Folder 8)
      - Des Pres, Terrence, 1976-1977 (Box 44, Folder 9)
      - French, Philip, 1977-1980 (Box 44, Folder 10)
      - Grumet, Elinor, 1976-1979 (Box 44, Folder 11)
      - Herman, George, 1979 February (Box 44, Folder 12)
      - Krupnick, Mark, 1976-1986 (Box 44, Folder 13)
      - Kubal, David, 1978-1979 (Box 44, Folder 14)
      - Lopate, Phillip, 1981 (Box 44, Folder 15)
      - Meyers, Jeffrey, 1981 (Box 44, Folder 16)
      - Platt, Michael, 1977-1979 (Box 44, Folder 17)
      - Salmet, Tom, 1977-1994 (Box 44, Folder 18)
      - Sennett, Richard, undated (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Shoben, Edward, 1980 (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Solotaroff, Theodore, 1976-1977 (Box 45, Folder 3)
      - Wald, Alan, 1946-1981 (Box 45, Folder 4)
      - Wellek, René, 1977-1979 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Lionel Trilling Reader, 1986-1996 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Lionel Trilling Seminars, 1995-1996 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Little, Brown and Company, 1974-1976 (Lillian Hellman controversy) (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Lopate, Phillip, 1994 (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Mailer, Norman, 1971 (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - "Making Double Judgments: The Criticism of Diana Trilling," 1995 (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - Marshall, Margaret, 1935-1945 (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - Memoir Excerpt, 1993 (Box 45, Folder 13)
    - McMurty, Larry, 1993-1994 (Box 45, Folder 14)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities Grant, 1976-1980 (Box 45, Folder 15)
    - New York Herald-Tribune" Response Letters, 1958 May-June (Box 45, Folder 16)
    - Op-Ed Magazine Proposal, 1995 January (Box 45, Folder 17)
    - Oral History
      - General, 1982-1987 (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Bentley, Eric, 1976 March 31 (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - Bentley, Eric, 1979 April 9 (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Donadio, Stephen, 1976 February 7 (Box 46, Folder 4)
      - Fadiman, Clifton, 1976 April 21 (Box 46, Folder 5)
      - Fadiman, Clifton, 1976 June 7 (Box 46, Folder 6)
      - Feiffer, Jules, 1976 July 20 (Box 46, Folder 7)
      - Ferber, Herbert, 1979 March 20 (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Fuchs, David, 1979 January 8 (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Goldwater, Walter--draft, 1979 January 4 (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - Goldwater, Walter--final, 1979 January 4-15 (Box 47, Folder 4 to 5)
      - Grossman, James and Elsa, 1976 January 24 (Box 47, Folder 6)
      - Grossman, James and Elsa, 1976 March 13 (Box 47, Folder 7)
      - Harrington, Michael
        - Draft, 1976 March 20 (Box 47, Folder 8)
        - Final, 1976 March 20 (Box 48, Folder 1)
        - "The Young Michael Harrington," 1976, 1990-1994 (Box 48, Folder 2)
      - Hays, Judge Paul R. and Elinor--draft, 1976 January 31 (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - Hays, Judge Paul R. and Elinor--final, 1976 January 31 (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - Hollander, John, 1976 January 27 (Box 48, Folder 5)
      - Hovde, Carl, 1976 March 17 (Box 48, Folder 6)
      - Howe, Irving, 1978 December 19 (Box 48, Folder 7)
      - Hunt, John, 1976 July 12 (Box 48, Folder 8)
      - Kristol, Bea, 1976 February 27 (Gertrude Himmelfarb) (Box 48, Folder 9)
      - Kunitz, Stanley, 1979 January 23 (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Lipman, Sam, 1979 September 14 (Box 49, Folder 2)
      - Macdonald, Dwight--draft, 1979 March 28 (Box 49, Folder 3)
      - Macdonald, Dwight--final, 1979 March 28 (Box 49, Folder 4)
      - Marcus, Steven, 1976 January 19 (Box 49, Folder 5)
      - Marcus, Steven, 1976 August 2-4 (Box 49, Folder 6)
      - Morrow, Felix, 1979 October 18 (Box 49, Folder 7)
      - Novack, George, 1978 May 11 (Box 50, Folder 1)
      - Phillips, William, 1976 March 28 (Box 50, Folder 2)
      - Rosenthal, Michael, 1976 January 13 (Box 50, Folder 3)
      - Rovere, Richard, 1978 December 7 (Box 50, Folder 4)
      - Schulman, Bob, 1976 February 29 (Box 50, Folder 5)
      - Shaw, Peter, 1979 April 6 (Box 50, Folder 6)
      - Stern, Fritz, 1976 February 10 (Box 50, Folder 7)
      - Thomson, Virgil, 1977 May 6 (Box 50, Folder 8)
      - Thompson, Jack and Susan, 1976 February 1 (Box 51, Folder 1)
      - Trilling, Diana, 1976 January-March (Box 51, Folder 2)
      - Trilling, Diana, 1979 January 9 (Box 51, Folder 3)
      - Warshaw, Paul, 1978 January 10 (Box 51, Folder 4)
      - White, Bede, 1976 April 14 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Other Authors, undated, 1929-1931, 1945, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Park, Catherine, 1995-1996 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Partial Bibliography, 1994-1996 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Performing Arts Book, 1992 (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Permissions
      - 1964-1979 (Box 51, Folder 10)
      - 1981-1990 (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - 1991-1996 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Podhoretz, Norman, 1980 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Professional Accolades, 1980-1994 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Publishers
      - General, 1972-1974 (Box 52, Folder 5)
      - A through C, 1957-1996 (Box 52, Folder 6)
      - D through H, 1957-1996 (Box 52, Folder 7)
      - N through O, 1957-1996 (Box 52, Folder 8)
      - P through S, 1957-1996 (Box 53, Folder 1)
      - U through V, 1957-1996 (Box 53, Folder 2)
      - V through W, 1957-1996 (Box 53, Folder 3)
      - Permissions, 1952-1976 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Publisher's Requests, 1991 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - Quentin Anderson Interview, 1984 February (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Reading at Lionel Trilling Seminar, 1985 (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - Rebecca West Biography, 1994-1995 (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - Recommendation Letters, 1978-1993 (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Rutgers University Press, 1993-1994 (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - Said, Edward, 1986 (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - Scottsboro Case, 1993 (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - Sidney Hook Biography, 1993 (Box 53, Folder 13)
    - Solotaroff, Theodore, 1961, 1976 (Box 53, Folder 14)
    - Sontag, Susan on Communism, 1982 (Box 53, Folder 15)
    - Trilling, Lionel--Funeral, 1975 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Videl, Gore, 1995 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Viking Press, 1970-1980 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - White House Dinner, 1962 April 29 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Subseries IV.2: Lionel Trilling, 1960-1996